<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boonedoggle</title>
    <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Boonedoggle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boonepeter.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building some-recipes.com</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/building-some-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/building-some-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Background Earlier this year I made my way through Fullstack Open, a course designed to teach modern Javascript-based web development.
In their words:
 The main focus is on building single page applications with ReactJS that use REST APIs built with Node.js. The course also contains a section on GraphQL, a modern alternative to REST APIs. The course covers testing, configuration and environment management, and the use of MongoDB for storing the application’s data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do Spotify Codes work?</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2020-11-10-spotify-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2020-11-10-spotify-codes/</guid>
      <description>Spotify Codes are QR-like codes that can be generated to easily share Spotify songs, artists, playlists, and users. I set out to figure out how they worked, which lead me on a winding journey through barcode history, patents, packet sniffing, error correction, and Gray tables.
Spotify URIs Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Spotify URIs (Uniform Resource Identifiers). Different pieces of media (artists, albums, songs, playlists, users) all have a URI.
The ABBA song &amp;ldquo;Take a Chance on Me&amp;rdquo; has this URI:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low mRNA levels in CHM patients</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2020-02-23-mrna-phenotype-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2020-02-23-mrna-phenotype-review/</guid>
      <description>The article: Association of Messenger RNA Level With Phenotype in Patients With Choroideremia: Potential Implications for Gene Therapy Dose
Background The central dogma of biology is simply that DNA makes RNA makes protein. Messenger RNA (mRNA) transfers the information from DNA and is used to create protein. The question this study ultimately seeks to answer is &amp;ldquo;How much mRNA is needed to have healthy retinal function in CHM patients?&amp;rdquo; It is important to know this information when conducting gene therapy clinical trials so an effective &amp;ldquo;dose&amp;rdquo; can be delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGCT Policy Summit, Day 3</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-11-16-asgct-gene-editing-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-11-16-asgct-gene-editing-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Washington, DC - Nov. 6, 2019
The American Society of Gene and Cell Therapy held a 3 day summit to discuss policy and other issues around gene editing and gene therapy.
 Day 1 addressed regulatory issues in gene therapy development Day 2 dealt with payment policies around gene therapy Day 3 (the day I attended) was focused on the ethical, societal, and policy issues around germline gene editing  Links to some of the presentations can be found on ASGCT&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Thursday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/05-18-19-arvo-2019-thursday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/05-18-19-arvo-2019-thursday-notes/</guid>
      <description>Panorama view from Whistler Mountain.
These notes from Thursday May 2, the last day of ARVO 2019. The conference had thinned out a bit as some people had to leave, but there were still some presentations of interest. You can read a summary or my notes from the other days here: Friday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday.
Papers Subfoveal gene augmentation therapy for choroideremia: One-year results from a Phase I/II trial of AAV2-hCHM - Rachel M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Thursday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-18-arvo-2019-thursday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-18-arvo-2019-thursday-notes/</guid>
      <description>Panorama view from Whistler Mountain.
These notes from Thursday May 2, the last day of ARVO 2019. The conference had thinned out a bit as some people had to leave, but there were still some presentations of interest. You can read a summary or my notes from the other days here: Friday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday.
Papers Subfoveal gene augmentation therapy for choroideremia: One-year results from a Phase I/II trial of AAV2-hCHM - Rachel M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Wednesday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-18-arvo-2019-wednesday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-18-arvo-2019-wednesday-notes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Digital Orca&amp;rdquo; sculpture outside of the Vancouver Convention Center.
These notes from May 1 are the continuation of a few articles about my time at ARVO. You can read a summary or my notes from the other days here: Friday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday.
Papers AAV2-hCHM Subretinal Delivery to the Macula in Choroideremia: 2 year Results of an Ongoing Phase I/II Gene Therapy Trial - Thomas Aleman Aleman presented more follow-up data from this phase I/II clinical trial that was performed on 10 CHM patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Summary</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-12-arvo-2019-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-12-arvo-2019-summary/</guid>
      <description>ARVO 2019 took place at the Vancouver Convention Center from April 28 to May 2 and featured novel work, continued efforts, and updates on clinical trials. On the Friday before ARVO the Foundation Fighting Blindness and the Casey Eye Institute hosted a summit featuring gene therapy, stem cell therapies, and non-viral therapies.
Randy Wheelock had been organizing a special interest group on Sunday to discuss combination therapies before his passing. Ian MacDonald and Chris Moen took over the organization of that event, which ended up being an honest discussion of the biggest obstacles researchers see ahead of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Tuesday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-12-arvo-2019-tuesday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-12-arvo-2019-tuesday-notes/</guid>
      <description>ARVO poster area B. Roughly 1,000 new posters are displayed every day of ARVO.
See my notes from Sunday and Monday.
Patient Engagement in Ophthalmology Research This special interest group discussed current methods of patient involvement in research and explored new ways this could be improved. A special emphasis was put on international policies, specifically in Europe and Canada. BC SUPPORT is one of the branches of the SPOR initiative across Canada meant to include patients and caregivers in research design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Monday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-11-arvo-2019-monday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-11-arvo-2019-monday-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Vancouver Convention Center&amp;rsquo;s East Building
These are my notes from the second day at ARVO 2019. Check out Sunday&amp;rsquo;s notes if you missed them.
Changing What it Means to be Blind: We&amp;rsquo;re All in This Together This session took place late in the evening and was put together by Kristin Smedley from the Curing Retinal Blindness Foundation. Smedley began the session by playing a TEDx talk she gave in 2017 at Lincoln Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2019 Sunday Notes</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-11-arvo-2019-sunday-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-05-11-arvo-2019-sunday-notes/</guid>
      <description>The Vancouver Convention Center&amp;rsquo;s West Building
A few words Similar to my article about the FFB Innovation Summit this post is a gathering of my notes from ARVO 2019. I will not be explaining topics, instead this is meant to be a reference for myself and others within the CRF. However I want these notes to be available to everyone since I think it is vitally important for those affected by disease to be invited into the discussion about research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 FFB Innovation Summit</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-27-ffb-innovation-summit-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-27-ffb-innovation-summit-2019/</guid>
      <description>Retinal Cell and Gene Therapy Innovation Summit The 6th annual Innovation Summit organized by the Foundation Fighting Blindness and the Casey Eye Institute at OHSU was packed with exciting research and over 300 attendees. The summit took place in Vancuover, CA on April 26 just before ARVO. I will highlight some research that was relevant to Choroideremia and a few notes on the work.
Gene Therapy Safety of Luxturna &amp;ndash; Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 CRF Special Interest Group</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-24-2018-crf-special-interest-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-24-2018-crf-special-interest-group/</guid>
      <description>The second article I wrote about ARVO 2018.
CRF Special Interest Group at ARVO 2018 The CRF organized and hosted a special session at the annual meeting of the Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology (ARVO) to discuss Choroideremia. This special session, organized by CRF president Dr. Chris Moen, was attended by over 100 researchers and clinicians. The discussion featured a panel consisting of Dr. Jacque Duncan, Dr. David Birch, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARVO 2018</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-24-arvo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/2019-04-24-arvo-2018/</guid>
      <description>Preface I will be attending ARVO 2019 shortly, so here is my experience from the 2018 conference that I wrote last year. You can also read this article for more detailed notes on the special interest group the CRF sponsored at ARVO.
ARVO 2018 The annual meeting of ARVO (the Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology) took place in Honolulu, Hawaii from April 28 to May 3, and was attended by over 11,000 researchers and clinicians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description>archive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
