<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bigquery on Peter Boone</title>
    <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/tags/bigquery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bigquery on Peter Boone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boonepeter.github.io/tags/bigquery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code In BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/advent_of_code_2022/</guid>
      <description>This year, I am be taking a page out of Felipe Hoffa&amp;rsquo;s book and will be attempting to complete the Advent of Code using BigQuery SQL. Until I reach the point where I can&amp;rsquo;t solve the puzzles with SQL, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep track of things here.
Day 1 WITH raw_input AS ( /* To start, I just copy/paste the input as a raw text string, and then parse that string into rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigQuery Resources</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/bigquery-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/bigquery-resources/</guid>
      <description>This is a living document of BigQuery resources that I have found useful (with some comments about their usefulness).
&amp;ldquo;Under the hood&amp;rdquo; articles Anatomy of a BigQuery Query: Why is BigQuery cool?
BigQuery under the hood: High-level descriptioon of how BigQuery is able to be so fast.
In memory query execution: If you like map reduce you should read this article. It talks about what is unique about BigQuery&amp;rsquo;s shuffle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing my genome</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/personal-genome-sequencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/personal-genome-sequencing/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since the Human Genome Project. This effort to sequence the human genome for the first time was a tremendous achievement that lasted 13 (ish) years and cost $3 billion dollars. Thanks to this pioneering work and major advancements over the years it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to get your own genome sequenced for $300 in a few months.
That&amp;rsquo;s a 10,000x decrease in cost! If the price of homes decreased at a similar rate since 1990, the median home would cost $7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NULL in BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/null-in-bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/null-in-bigquery/</guid>
      <description>When in doubt, NULL means &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t know the state of this thing so we can&amp;rsquo;t perform an operation on it.&amp;rdquo;
Keeping track of how NULL values are handled in different SQL dialects can be tricky. This post will serve as a living document where I keep track of how BigQuery does this.
NULL and STRING comparison Comparison always returns NULL.
SELECT CAST(NULL AS STRING) = &amp;#39;&amp;#39;, -- null CAST(NULL AS STRING) = &amp;#39;value&amp;#39;, -- null CAST(NULL AS STRING) = CAST(NULL AS STRING) -- null NULL and BOOL comparison NULL is not TRUE or FALSE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The practical use of repetition and definition levels in BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/bigquery-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/bigquery-records/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s Dremel paper is an interesting read that explains some of the concepts that underlie BigQuery. I am still processing the paper and have noticed a few things about repetition and definition levels that are relevant to the every day use of BigQuery.
Columnar Data and Records The underlying storage format for BigQuery is columnar. One of the first pieces of advice given to people using BigQuery is to only select the rows that you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unnecessary BigQuery Optimization</title>
      <link>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/unnecessary_bigquery_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boonepeter.github.io/posts/unnecessary_bigquery_optimization/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a post about BigQuery cost optimization which stated this:
Also remember you are charged for bytes processed in the first stage of query execution. Avoid creating a complex multistage query just to optimize for bytes processed in the intermediate stages, since there are no cost implications anyway (though you may achieve performance gains).
I was curious about this, because I have written some queries to minimize reading data multiple times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
